# JEFFREY ABOH

Full Stack Developer - https://jeffreyaboh.co.uk

Abuja, Nigeria

jeffrey@myethion.com

+2349053448854

Dedicated and efficient Full Stack Developer with 5+ years experience in application layers, presentation layers, and databases. Certified in both F/E and B/E technologies. I am very familiar and experienced with Web Application Architecture and have worked with a good number of successful development teams.

#readytowork

Authorized to work in the US for any employer



### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### MOBILE APPLICATION DEVELOPER

**Brandz Digital** 

February 2020 to Present

- Develop Mobile Applications for both Android & iOS using Ionic Framework & React Native.
- Perform Testing on Mobile Applications before they are deployed.

Website: www.brandz.digital Email: hello@brandz.digital

#### **CEO/FOUNDER**

Ethion Website Builder, (ETHION TECHNOLOGIES RC: 2810094) - Nigeria

2017 to Present

- I built Ethion, an A.I Online Website Builder. A DIY (Do-It-Yourself) Platform with easy Drag and Drop tools for building a stunning professional website.
- I also handle general operations at Ethion.
- Use various ideas from distributed computing, large-scale design, real-time data processing, data storage, ML, and AI to solve challenging dataset problems.

Website: www.myethion.com Email: info@myethion.com

### FREELANCE FULL STACK DEVELOPER

2015 to Present

- I currently work as a freelance full stack developer and i have worked on different projects for individuals and organizations from time to time.
- Developed full-stack web applications which processed, analyzed, and rendered data visually.
- Planned, wrote, and debugged web applications and software with complete accuracy.

Online Portfolio: https://jeffreyaboh.co.uk

## PHP DEVELOPER (CONTRACT)

**Autogrow** - New York, NY March 2020 to March 2020

• Worked on the autogrow app specifically areas that has to do with authentication & security leveraging the use of PHP and Codeigniter.

Website: www.autogrow.co

### REMOTE DEVELOPER (CONTRACT)

Adewale Ibrahim College of Health Science - Nigeria

August 2019 to September 2019

- I work on contract basis handling the college's database, I built and manage it's websites, application portal and internal management portal. I also provide support on IT related issues.
- Developed app integration with REST / SOAP and other APIs for Google Maps, social media logins, payment processors, and other services.
- Maximized applications' efficiency, data quality, scope and flexibility.

Website: www.aicohs.com.ng Email: info@aicohs.com.ng

#### REMOTE DEVELOPER

ARETON LIMITED - United Kingdom

2018 to 2019

- I worked for Areton Limited as a remote developer working on development/management of it's various websites, web applications, online presence and general IT related tasks.
- Managed time-sensitive updates, including content changes and database upgrades.

Website: www.areton-ltd.com Email: info@areton-ltd.com

### WEB DEVELOPER (INTERN)

Aiivon Global Innovations - Nigeria

March 2018 to September 2018

- I built and develop websites and web applications for clients, handle clients technical request and provide support to client and other developers in the organization.
- Managed, optimized, and updated databases as necessary.
- Liaised with back end developers, front end developers, quality assurance testers, and CTO as needed.

Website: www.aiivon.com Email: hello@aiivon.com



**EDUCATION** 

#### **Bachelor's in COMPUTER SCIENCE**

**BINGHAM UNIVERSITY** 

2015 to 2019

# **Diploma in INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY**

#### **KHEMSAFE INSTITUTE**

2014 to 2015



SKILLS

- HTML
- css
- PHP
- JavaScript
- Bootstrap
- Angular JS
- JQuery
- SQL Databases
- Google Compute Engine
- Android and iOS App Development
- APIs
- ASP.Net
- C#
- Ionic Framework
- WordPress
- Content Management Systems
- SEO
- Linux
- Git
- REST
- Agile
- MySQL
- REST
- Node.js
- React Native



LINKS

https://github.com/jeffreyaboh

https://jeffreyaboh.co.uk

https://join.skype.com/invite/jNjdm5Clad2c

https://techpoint.africa/2017/08/24/adspro-profile/

https://www.linkedin.com/in/jeffery-aboh-50971b84/



### CERTIFICATIONS AND LICENSES ......

#### CERTIFICATION IN COMPUTER APPLICATIONS AND GOOGLE APPS

2015 to Present

**BINGHAM UNIVERSITY** 



#### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Jeffrey Aboh loves programming, writing, speaking, traveling, and lifting heavy things. He does not love talking about himself in the 3rd person. He is the founder of Ethion Technologies, a registered company that provides Web Development, Software Development and other I.C.T Professional Services including General Contracts. He worked as Head Developer for Areton Limited, United Kingdom and got his B.Sc at Bingham University, Nigeria.

A front-end/back-end developer's role is to combine design, codes and business logic to achieve a user-facing and advanced product. To do this successfully, a wide skill set is necessary to produce a quality user experience and advanced features that leads to meeting business goals. With my experience I can!